Andrei Tuta

github.com/andreituta linkedin.com/in/andreituta Email: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com

Mobile: +40725565620

Skype: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com

## CAREER PROFILE

A passionate Software Developer with extensive and diversified experience in developing mobile applications, websites, web applications and offering administration services for local businesses.

Knowledge of product-life-cycle management, business development and leading cross-functional teams was gained while managing various other projects and business ideas, focusing on understanding existing and emerging technologies, Software as a Service (SaaS), while minimizing their cost and administering workload.

## Professional experience

### • URJ 6 Points Sci-tech

Byfield, MA

Counselor/Specialist

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- o Counselor: Camp counselor, tasked with managing and leading daily activities.
- **Programming assistant**: Helping instructors with running the Programming and Coding workshop, focused on teaching programming in Processing for developing their own projects.
- Workshop Instructor: Running my own workshop, in which participants learned the basic syntax of HTML, CSS, JS and the logic behind coding a virtual Monopoly game.

# • Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Programming assistant Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Java demonstrator: Helped groups of students during their laboratory sessions. Tasks involved explaining concepts and helping with debugging their projects.
- Innovation Fest Mentor: Managed and helped two teams of students with the technical development, planning and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest.

• Oracle Romania Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun - Sep 2017

- Oracle DBA training: Part of the internship consisted of a training similar to a complete DBA course. During this training, topics such as basic administration, back-up, recovery and automation were covered.
- Administrator: After the training was completed, I completely installed and automated two separate databases to execute all the required procedures.

## • The Business Information Portal

Birmingham, UK

Software Developer

Oct 2015 - Sep 2016

- Part-time development: Worked within an small scale team to develop solutions for people with a visual impairment. Gained experience working within a large code base and improved at writing clean, testable code. Another area of development was writing Arduino and IoT code.
- **Testing**: Applied Agile methodologies and CI processes with Test Driven Development for software development in various environments. Learned the importance of risk management in software: continuous builds, Quality Assurance and release cycles .

#### EDUCATION

## • Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

B.Sc. in Computer Science - Data Analysis. Machine Learning and Database administration

2015 - 2018

#### • Universidad de Alcala

Alcala de Henares, Spain

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Erasmus semester in Spain

Jan - Jun 2017

## PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Kotlin, SQL Technologies: AWS, React, Android Studio, MongoDB

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• Outward Mobility Ambassador, BCU CEBE	Jan - Jun 2018
Managing, assisting and recruiting students for international programs and social media development	
• President, BCU RoSoc  Event planning, budgeting & team management	2016 - 2018
• Secretary, Rotaract Club Birmingham  Event planning, PR & note-taking	2015 - 2017